This is the CEO of the parent company of
Trader Joe's in Aldi. He has just
finished work and is heading home for
the day. Parked next to him is a
Mercedes 280, the same model his boss is
driving, but it appears to be someone
else's car. His boss left earlier
anyways and should long be home by now.
What he can't see is that his boss is
tied up in the back seat just 3 m away
from him, gagged and held at gunpoint.
He has been kidnapped and this really is
his car. This right here is the
beginning of the biggest kidnapping in
German history.
The man in the back seat is Teao
Albreth, one of the two brothers who
founded the global discount supermarket
chain Aldi and one of the richest people
in Europe. At this point in time, Aldi
is already taking over Germany. Soon
it'll conquer the world. Tea Albreth and
his brother will forever change the way
people do grocery shopping, how much
they spend on it, and how supermarkets
work in general.
But right now, he's not thinking about
business. He's thinking about staying
alive.
[Music]
Myster.
This is Teao and this is his brother
Carl. They're the Alrech brothers. Their
parents own a small grocery shop in the
West German city of Essen. It's small
and simple. The brothers grow up helping
out where they can, but it's a tough
time for selling groceries or anything
really. There was the hyperinflation in
1923, the Great Depression of 1929,
Germany bombed to rebel in 1945, and the
currency reform of 1948. Most Germans
are broke and hungry. Teao is in his
mid20s when he and Carl take over the
family shop. They know they have to be
smart to make it through these difficult
times. In this barebones store, the two
will develop a set of principles that
will revolutionize the concept of
supermarkets as we know it.
This is Hana. She's in her early 20s and
from another West German city called
Dusseldorf. She comes from money and
right now she's head over heels in love
with this guy. He's a bit older, as in
almost 30 years older. A lawyer with a
firm in downtown Dusseldorf. He too is
rich. He drives flashy cars, takes
luxury vacations, and somehow always
wins at the roulette table. Well, almost
always. The other day, his luck ran out.
He had to borrow 300,000 Deutsche marks
from Hana. But that's not going to
bother her tonight. Tonight, they'll
enjoy themselves at a ball.
Hana will have this photo framed and put
up in her bedroom. She has no idea it'll
go global just a few months later.
Interpol will use it for their manhunt
to bring down the mastermind behind
Germany's most high-profile kidnapping.
Hana's big shot lawyer boyfriend is
called Hines Yuim Olenborg. And right
now he's got a problem. He and his
partner just kidnapped one of the
richest men in the country.
and they have absolutely no idea what to
do next. To be fair, it's their first
kidnapping. Also, Olenberg's day job is
entirely different. He forged his high
school diploma to get into law school.
He's been divorced twice and keeps
having affairs with young women. These
days, he's representing pretty shitty
clients, lone sharks, small-time crooks,
and professional criminals. Now, he
needs cash, lots of it, and fast.
700,000 Deutsche marks. He owes not only
Hana a couple of grand, but also a few
relatives and even two serious felons.
One of them is this guy here, Diamond
Paul. His real name is Paul Kron. He's a
trained car mechanic by day and a safe
cracker by night. He breaks into banks
and department stores and snatches their
cash deposits. He got caught once and
did a few years behind bars. He swore he
was done with that life when he got out,
but he still has that one dream, a house
on the Spanish Mediterranean coast. He
even has a name for it, Casapollo. The
land is already paid for. Now he just
needs the money to build it. But his day
job pays less than 2,000 Deutsche marks
a month. That is not going to cut it.
The kidnapping was his idea. One last
job and they go off grid forever.
The morning after the kidnapping, they
don't know where to stash their
millionaire. So Paul spent the night
with him in his garage with Teao Alrech
tied up and blindfolded next to him in
the passenger seat. Alrech's wife
already knows. They called her the night
before the kidnapping. They promised her
husband would come back unharmed as long
as she stayed quiet. No cops, no press.
Now they just need to figure out what to
do with him. First, they need to bring
him somewhere safe, quietly so that no
one will recognize him. But how do you
move a hostage without anyone noticing?
They weigh their options. A wardrobe
trunk? Too small. A broom closet? 6
weeks delivery time. Roll them up in a
carpet. That could work. Olenberg heads
out to get one. 2x3 m. Kron stays in the
car with Alrech. They agree to meet at a
quiet road where they can safely
transfer Alrech into a Volkswagen van.
The plan is to make him sit on the
rolled out rug and wrap him up like a
burrito.
It all starts with this butter.
Postwar Germany is a country in ruins.
Food is scarce. Butter is a luxury. So
the Obre brothers do something unusual.
They sell their butter at cost. Without
markups and profits, sometimes even at
loss. But word spreads quickly. There's
no cheaper butter in town than at the
Albre shop. Butter becomes their draw or
what's often called a loss leader. Other
oblast leaders are bread, margarine,
milk, flour, potatoes, pasta, soap, and
toilet paper. Their everyday essentials
at unbeatable prices. And once customers
come in for those, they're likely to
also spend money on other products. The
plan works out. Before long, the obl one
grocery store after another. Within just
a few years, they're running 30
supermarkets across the greater area.
While scaling, Aldi keeps it old school.
A lot of paper, a lot of folders,
tightly managed departments. If only
they could have run on UDu, the
all-in-one management platform. Instead
of isolated softwares, tons of
individual applications, and lost files,
Udu lets you manage all aspects of
business in a central hub. And if you're
still hesitating, Udu's website app is
the perfect launchpad. You can create a
website in just four steps. Use the drag
and drop builder to create a custom site
in minutes. Personalize your text and
choose the perfect font. Drop in your
own images or grab some from the free
Unsplash library. Easily add animations.
Adapt your layout with the grid system
and customize your backgrounds with
shapes and gradient filters. Start using
UD's website app for free today. Your
first app is free for life, including
unlimited hosting and support, plus a
free custom domain name for a year. Add
more apps anytime and get access to the
full suite from just €19.90 per month.
Click the link in the description to get
started.
Olenberg and Kron are looking for a
place to hide their kidnapped
millionaire in broad daylight in
downtown Dudeldorf. The first idea is
Owen Burke's lawyer's office, but it's
located on a busy street right in the
city center just off the central
station. Getting Albe out of the car and
into the building would mean walking him
across the sidewalk blindfolded so he
doesn't see where he's taken and by
whom. He could shout. People could
notice and get suspicious.
The second idea is Olenberg's grown-up
daughter. She lives only a few blocks
away. They could hide him there and have
her move into the lawyer's office for a
while. But that's probably a tough cell.
Her father has never visited her
apartment, not even once. And now he
would just show up with a kidnapped
millionaire. So, back to the first idea.
Unfortunately, Albreth doesn't fit in
the rug. What now? The hostage himself
ends up pitching in. He promises to
cooperate and not cause trouble.
Alenberg and Cron agree. They take off
the blindfold, tape his eyes with skin
patches, and give him a pair of shades.
Then, they walk him across the sidewalk
to the building. But there's another
problem. The office is packed with staff
and clients who have already been
waiting a while. So Alenberg shuffles
everyone into back room so that Kron can
sneak Alrech through the hallway and
into Alenberg's private room. He usually
reserves it for secret dates with his
younger girlfriends. The room is a
cramped 4 square meter al cove. They sit
Alrech down on the bed. Then Alenberg
goes into full gear to clear the office,
rushing through client meetings and
sending his staff home early. They don't
mind.
Hana is worried as usual. Not because
she thinks her boyfriend is a kidnapper,
but because she knows he's a womanizer,
constantly chasing younger women.
But tonight, he comes home from work on
time. There's nothing special on the
evening news. No mentions of a missing
tycoon.
Mrs. Albre seems to have gotten the
message. No police and no press.
Carl Albreth steps onto a small stage.
He's about to give a rare public speech.
He talks to fellow grocerers about how
he and his brother grew their business
from 1 to 30 stores within just a few
years. It'll be the first and last time
he publicly explains the Albreth
business model.
Looking back on our operations, I see
that in the early days, we were forced
to keep a small product range. The sales
strategy includes only fastmoving
consumer goods. The limited product
range eliminates time-conuming
consultations for our staff, and
customers can decide much faster to
either buy or not buy. For example, we
don't carry loose jams, fresh fruits,
and vegetables because they slow down
sales. We also skip canned fruits and
vegetables and specialty items like
mayonnaise, pickled herring, herring
salad and so on because of turnover
speed. We carry only one variety of each
product. For legumes, we have just one
type each. So only one kind of beans,
one kind of lentils and one kind of
rice. For shoe polish, we only carry a
doll for toothpaste only blends and only
sigella for floor wicks and cans. So for
brand products, we only ever carry the
bestselling brands. We have followed
this principle of small product ranges
at low prices since 1950. The customer
must believe they cannot buy cheaper
anywhere else. Once that belief is in
place, and I think we achieved just
that, customers will accept about
anything.
Tea Alrech spends most of his
confinement sitting on the bed in his
undershirt and briefs. He gets bread
rolls for breakfast, steak with potatoes
and beans for lunch, and coffee and
pastries at tea time. The kidnappers
offer him a warm meal for dinner, but he
just wants sandwiches and mineral water.
Every 2 days, he gets a hot bath and
fresh underwear. He's allowed to shave
with one of the kidnappers razors. They
took his suit and shirt to a dry
cleaner, so it look decent on the day of
his release. His captors dictate letters
for him to write to his wife.
Dear silly, you have heard from me by
now. I want to assure you again that I'm
doing fine and that I'm being treated
fairly. Please don't worry. Everything
will be okay. I beg you not to call the
police at any circumstance and to not
involve the press. I'll explain the
terms of my release later. Much love.
You're Theo.
4 days in and the kidnappers still
haven't addressed the ransom. Olenberg
keeps dodging the topic, saying it makes
him uncomfortable. And just like that,
another day goes by in captivity. Alreth
will later testify in court that during
those days he lived in constant fear for
his life.
Day five, Saturday. Albert decides to
take matters into his own hands. He
proposes a ransom. By this time, Aldi is
estimated to be generating 2 billion
Deutsche marks in yearly revenue. But
the price tag he puts on his own life is
considerably smaller, 100,000 Deutsche
marks. It's a ridiculous offer, a joke.
Then again, it's very on brand. Tail
Alrech is famously stingy.
[Music]
Daily business at the Elre stores is
governed by a set of strict principles.
One, no heating. Employees are expected
to dress warmly. Two, lights off unless
absolutely necessary. Tail personally
ensures compliance during frequent
surprise rounds. Three, zero waste.
Every sheet of paper is used front and
back. Plastic sleeves get reused. Paper
clips and envelopes are meticulously
saved. Four, no frrills, no decoration,
no pretty product displays, no fancy
signage, just fluorescent lighting and
cardboard boxes stacked on plain
shelves. Five, speed, or what some may
call German. No chitchat, no customer
consultation, no service counters, just
rapid checkouts. Time is money. Even the
bathrooms are optimized. Tailbreath has
all electronic hand dryers replaced
because they take 4 seconds too long to
shut off. Refrigeration is too expensive
as well. The butter that fueled Aldi's
meteoric rise is sold at room
temperature. At night, it's stored in a
cool basement. All of this serves one
goal and one goal only. Rock bottom
prices. Affordable for anyone.
[Music]
Aldi
market. The Alre grocery business
eventually turns into Aldi, the discount
giant that's also behind Trader Joe's.
And Aldi becomes a force of nature, a
retail machine that leverages its market
power to squeeze suppliers and farmers
for ever lower prices. The Alrech
brothers earn a reputation as brutally
efficient negotiators. But right now,
Teao Alreth is not the one negotiating
from a position of power. The guys
across the table have a gun and they're
threatening to kill him. They flat out
reject his initial offer. Olenberg knows
exactly how rich Alreth is. He read
about it in a book. That's how they
picked him up in the first place.
Olenberg tells Alrech they need to
consult with their partners. First, Kron
heads into the next room for a call,
then the calls are fake. There's no one
on the other end. They're bluffing to
push the ransom. Alenberg tells Alrech
he and his partners have agreed on a
number. He says there are seven people
involved and that a million each would
be fair. That makes 7 million. At this
point, it's the largest sum ever
demanded in a kidnapping in Europe.
Olenberg tells Alrech not to worry. He
can probably tax deduct the money as a
business expense. Bre agrees. It's not
like he really has a choice.
By now, the kidnappers have worked out a
plan for the ransom drop. On Tuesday at
exactly 4 p.m. they'll call the Alrech
residents. Waiting on the other end will
be the four people involved in the
handover. Alrech's wife Silly, the
family lawyer, the company's managing
director, and one of his sons. They'll
be given a first location, Meisenberg
Street in Essen. There will be two
stones with a note hidden underneath.
The note will lead them to another
location where they'll find another note
with another direction. The same thing
will happen two more times. The final
note will read,
>> "Continue along the B288 toward Essen.
Pull over at the parking lot near the
Wai Bridge and use the deposited radio
transmitter. Press the right button to
say, "To, come in, please." Then follow
the instructions you'll receive over the
radio. Kron will guide them via
walkie-talkie to a path in the woods.
There, they're supposed to drop the
money and leave. When the coast is
clear, Kron will grab the ransom and
Albert will be released at Frankfurt
airport. They'll tell him they're
leaving the country. Alreth is told to
board a plane back to Dusseldorf. Once
he lands, he's a free man. And the
kidnappers will have supposedly fled
somewhere far away. It's a solid plan.
Even Alrech feels a bit relieved.
SM Police Headquarters. These are the
four people awaiting the instructions
for the ransom drop. At least they're
supposed to look the part. They're
actually four undercover detectives.
They've been disguised by theater makeup
artists. One of them is dressed as Mrs.
Albrech and wearing a wig. Underneath
the costumes, they're hiding bulletproof
vests and guns. They're standing by and
waiting for the signal.
Kron makes the call to the Albreth
residence. He says hello and is about to
give the first set of instructions and
immediately gets cut off. Mrs. Albreth
was the one supposed to answer the call,
but it's the family's lawyer on the
line.
>> Please listen carefully. I have a brief
but important statement to make. The
conditions you have set are
unacceptable. Money is the only viable
exchange for the hostage. Since you
demanded an unusually high amount of
ransom money, we had to notify the state
central bank. They in turn informed the
police and the press is also aware of
the situation. We must act quickly now.
Name a drop location and a reasonable
amount. You will have our word. You will
receive the money and be given enough
time by the police to disappear.
>> Police and the press. That's the worst
case scenario. Kron rejects and hangs
up. The Alrech family and the
investigators are startled, too. They've
spooked the kidnappers and lost their
trust. Tail Alrech's life is still very
much on the line. What now?
This is Hungbach. He's the bishop of
Essen, and this is the city's chief of
police. He desperately needs someone
neutral that everyone can trust. The
police, the family, and most
importantly, the kidnappers. someone who
can be handed 7 million Deutsch marks
and promise the kidnappers not to set
them up. The plan is to use the
Christian seal of confession. According
to German criminal law, clergy are not
obligated to report crimes they learn
about during spiritual counsel. This
will hopefully give the kidnappers a bit
more assurance. Maybe they really can
walk away clean. Which is why Bishop
Hensbach shall handle the money handoff
and save Tail Alrech's life. Hangs is a
man of faith. Of course, he agrees. The
kidnappers also agree to the plan.
Technically, everything is set for a
clean and smooth handover.
Technically,
the press has known about the case for a
while now and agreed to keep quiet upon
police request. But when they find out
about the bishop becoming the middleman,
they can't resist any longer. It's just
too good of a story.
The Essen police and prosecutors are
forced to call a press conference. The
room is packed.
[Music]
Now it's not just the police anymore.
The entire world knows what's happening.
The bishop has been compromised. The
kidnappers call off the meeting. It's
too risky. The Alrech family is
desperate. They've lost all contact with
the kidnappers. Will they harm Theo?
Their last hope for communication is to
include a message in a popular show on
German national TV.
Hana is doing okay, but she's worried
about her boyfriend. He hasn't been
sleeping well and says work has been
stressful lately. At least they can
unwind in front of the TV.
for
[Music]
bitter. The handleb
>> business in Germany keeps booming and
Carl Albrech sets his sights on
expansion. In 1967, his branch of the
business called Aldis takes its first
steps abroad, buying up Austrian
supermarket chain, Hoffer with 30 shops.
His brother Teo follows suit 6 years
later, opening the first Aldi Nort store
in the Dutch city of Ulteram. Soon they
expand to Belgium and France, conquering
Europe one country at a time.
But right now, Carl Orbeth has to take a
very different kind of call. He's on the
phone with one of the men who has
kidnapped his brother, and the guy is
furious. The ransom drop off has to
happen now, clean and fast. They settle
on a new time and place. The kidnappers
agree to let Bishop Hanksbuff deliver
the money. After all, is to stay with
him for 24 hours after the exchange. No
police. Any interference could be fatal.
Carl agrees.
Back at the office, Kron returns with
the good news. The deal is back on, but
Olenberg has other concerns. He knows
the police are recording their calls.
He's been obsessing over security and
telling his accomplice countless times
to take precautions. So, just to be
sure, he asks Kron if he really changed
his voice. Kron shrugs awkwardly. Yeah,
kind of.
Day 17 of the abduction. Tonight's the
night the handover is finally supposed
to happen. tail breath in exchange for 7
million Deutsche marks. A lonely dirt
road just off the highway. There's an
overpass and two exit roads close by.
Perfect escape conditions. The
kidnappers arrive. Albreth is wearing
skin patches over his eyelids,
sunglasses, and an old hat from
Olenberg. They had a glass of sparkling
wine to mark the occasion. Enberg even
gave Albreth two parting gifts. The
three step out and wait for over an
hour. Is this a setup after all?
Finally, a Volkswagen rolls up with
Essen plates. The two men step out in
clerical coats. One of them is
unmistakably Bishop Hensbach. The family
fears a double cross. What if this is
not the real Theo? What if the
kidnappers pass off a decoy and run off
with the money? So, the bishop has to
test him with three questions dictated
by Theo's wife. What kind of wood is
Alre's new bedroom wardrobe made of?
Alreth hesitates. That damn wardrobe.
What was the name of that wood again? He
gives his answer, but the bishop shakes
his head. Wrong.
The second question is about an
acquaintance they made during vacation.
He gets that one right. And the third
one, too. All right, close enough. This
has to be the real Teao Elreth. The
bishop and his driver get the money from
the car. 7 million Deutsche marks in
cash wrapped like Christmas presents.
Olenberg and Kron wish them merry
Christmas, hand over the Aldi founder,
and vanish. No one follows them. They
did it. They're now multi-millionaires.
[Music]
And Germany's most wanted criminals.
Tea Albreth is a free man. 17 days after
his abduction, he's finally back. He
just keeps doing what he does best,
expand his empire. In 1979, he sets his
sights on the US market and buys Trader
Joe's. Then he enforces the same
principles that made Aldi so successful,
a limited product range, strong private
labels, and aggressive pricing. The
formula works. Trader Joe's grows from a
quirky California chain into a
nationwide cold supermarket with
hundreds of locations and billions in
revenue. His brother had already opened
the first US Aldi store 3 years earlier.
Theo operates under the banner of his
branch Aldi Nord and Carl under Aldi
Zud. They're technically competitors but
with different customer bases. Today,
Aldi is the fastest growing grocery
retailer in the US and the main reason
people shop there is the same as ever.
>> Hello, unbeatable prices.
>> Aldi doesn't play pricing games on USDA
Choice Beef. They have low prices every
day.
>> Hana is waiting for her boyfriend. She's
packed a suitcase. He said he was going
on vacation without her. And now he's
late. Maybe he's seeing someone else.
When he finally gets home, his shoes are
soaking and his pants are covered in
mud. Hm. How would you get your pants
that dirty at a downtown office? But
Olenberg can't exactly tell her that he
just pulled off a spectacular kidnapping
and that his pants are dirty because he
just buried 1.5 million Deutsche marks
in the woods. So, he just says nothing.
His thoughts are already elsewhere
anyway, with his other girlfriend, his
one true love, the woman he plans to run
away with, all the way to the other side
of the world, where they'll use that
money to start a new life. But Hana will
soon find out what those dirty pants
were really about.
Paul is at his sister's house. Her
husband is there, too. They're having
coffee and cake, and the TV is on with
sound.
So, it's true the police really did
record the phone call between Kron and
Carl Alrech. Now, the city's district
attorney is playing it to the German
press. He's hoping to get help from the
public that someone out there will
recognize the kidnapper's voice.
Dr.
Kron's sister instantly recognizes her
brother's voice. No doubt about it. He's
the only kidnapper the entire country is
looking for. That's a tough thing to
explain over coffee and cake. Kron
doesn't even try. He just gets up and
leaves. Hana recognizes the voice, too.
Olenberg has invited Kron over for
dinner many times. She knows exactly who
that is.
A small electronic store in Dusseldorf.
The shopkeeper turns on the TV just to
catch a segment of a show called Here
and Today. They're also playing the
recording of the Ali's kidnappers voice,
and it sounds very familiar.
Just the day before, a man with that
exact voice had come in to pay off his
installment plan. He even bought a
stereo system for 3,400 Deutsche marks
on top. The shopkeeper calls the police.
Before the handoff, investigators had
written down the serial numbers of all
500 Deutsche Mark bills in the ransom
bundle. Three of those bills were used
in the electronic store. It's a match.
Paul Cron is arrested 2 days later, but
the second kidnapper is still a mystery
and still at large.
Peter Spore is a young police trainee
working toward his detective badge.
Right now he's doing an internship with
the Essen Criminal Police. This is his
mentor, Chief Inspector Fried Helm Misa.
They're sitting in a lawyer's office on
the fourth floor of the Graph Adolf
Street 45. It's run by the lawyer
representing Paul Cron. It's not exactly
a hot lead for the two policemen. The
more exciting assignments had already
been snatched up by others. There's a
pub downstairs on the ground floor of
the building. Good cops think
strategically, so first a beer and then
a plan.
Tea Alrech never knew where exactly he
had been held, but he told the police
every detail he could remember. An
elevator in the stairwell, a narrow
bathroom with a double sink and a broken
extractor fan, the sound of street cars
passing by, and a bell chiming at
regular intervals.
The policemen see a street car passing
by outside the lawyer's office. Then
they hear the church bell of a nearby
coven just like an Alre description.
They peek into the building stairwell.
Bingo, an elevator. So they check out
the construction plan from the city's
building department. The bathroom is
long and narrow. They get a warrant to
search the office. Everything inside
exactly matches Alrech's memories.
Meanwhile, Kron starts to crack.
[Music]
This is Blondie, a 19-year-old legal
assistant. She's waiting for her
boyfriend at Whooper Tall Central
Station. She hasn't seen him in weeks,
but he promised her something big, a
luxury vacation in Mexico to celebrate
that she successfully passed her
training, two full weeks. Hines Yokim
Olenberg is on the run. He knows the
cops have already picked up Kron. It's
only a matter of time before they find
out that he's the second Aldi kidnapper.
Olenberg and Blondie have known each
other for over a year when she spent a
few months working from the US. He
started killing time with Hana, but his
heart always belonged to Blondie.
They're madly in love with each other.
Now they're on their way to Frankfurt
airport.
Back in Essen, Hana has no idea. She's
alone at home when suddenly the police
is at her door. They're looking for
Alenberg. They seize this photo. It will
become the official manhunt photo. Once
they realize Olenberg has left the
country, the case goes global. The
picture is sent to Interpol and
investigators in over a 100 countries.
Olenberg is now one of the most wanted
men on the planet. And Hana finally
learns the truth that her charming lover
owes her over 300,000 marks. That he
kidnapped the founder of Aldi, locked
him up in his office, and then came home
to her every night as if nothing
happened. all while secretly planning
his escape with a girl from Whooper he's
been sleeping with all this time.
Shortly after, Hana walks into a police
station and hands them her boyfriend's
dirty pants. Maybe there's something on
them that will help them bring him down.
A luxury hotel in Mexico City. Olenberg
and Blondie have spent a quiet first
night together. Now he's supposed to
plan their next days, but deep down he's
thinking about something else. He could
tell Blondie everything, the whole
story. They could run first to Cuba, a
country that surely doesn't extradite to
Germany, and then disappear to some
remote Pacific island. But would Blondie
really leave everything behind for him,
her whole life, her family?
It's 12:00 a.m. now, and Blondie is
waiting for her boyfriend in the hotel
lobby. She's coming off a travel group
meeting. He said he'd freshen up for
lunch and meet her downstairs, but he
doesn't show up. Turns out her boyfriend
has just been arrested by agents of the
Mexican Federal Police. Paul Kron has
thrown him under the bus. Blondie is
stunned, unable to process what's
happening, but all signs point to a
shocking truth. Her boyfriend is the
mastermind behind the spectacular
kidnapping of Teo Alra, the crime that's
been dominating headlines in Germany for
weeks. So much for a vacation. They're
on the flight back to Europe when she
confesses her love. She'll wait for him
even if he ends up going to jail.
Hines Yuake Olenborg is sentenced to 8
and a2 years in prison.
[Music]
Aldi stands for a promise. We'll do
everything we can to make sure you pay
as little as possible. For millions of
people living from paycheck to paycheck
around the globe, that promise is a
lifeline. At Aldi, they're able to
afford things they otherwise couldn't.
But that promise comes at a cost.
Workers operate under enormous pressure
because in Aldi stores, every second
counts. According to one report,
cashiers are expected to scan 55 items
per minute. Customers can barely keep up
with bagging. Low prices means high
pressure, not just for staff, but also
for manufacturers, suppliers, and
farmers. If you want to work with Aldi,
you have to deliver. Aldi and other
discounters wield staggering market
power. They can just raise food prices
without passing profits down the supply
chain to producers and farmers. Farming
businesses in particular have long been
criticizing unfair business practices.
Many say they're at the mercy of the
retailer's whims. Tailre's brilliant and
often brutal methods made him one of the
richest people on Earth. He ranked 31st
on the corresponding Forbes list by the
time he died. The kidnapping left a mark
though. Albreth pretty much disappeared
from the public after that. He really
did try to write off the ransom as a
business expense. The tax office in
Dudeldorf declined. Half of the ransom
money has never been recovered. Kron
claimed he only ever got 10,000 marks.
Olenberg also played dumb, but some
believe he lived off the rest of the
ransom after having served his time.
Whether Blondie really waited for him
all those years, we may never know.